A Guide to the Joseph H. Crooks Papers, 1937-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Joseph H. Crooks Papers, 1937-1997
The Library of Virginia
44219
6.3 cubic feet (22 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Elizabeth Carol Wells Stevenson, Ashland.
Biographical Information
Joseph Hatchitt Crooks was born on 21 September 1908 in Manchester, Virginia. He was the son of William B. Crooks (1866-1951) and Cornelia Hatchitt Farley (1870-1957). He died in Richmond, Virginia on 31 July 2007, and is buried in Forest Lawn Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1937-1997, of Joseph H. Crooks (1908-2007) of Richmond, Virginia, including his genealogical research files on the Crooks, Ellington, Farley, Fowlkes, Gills, Hatchitt, and Owings families of Amelia, Chesterfield, Lunenburg, Nottoway, and Prince Edward Counties, Virginia, and Baltimore County, Maryland. The files include family group sheets, and notebooks with abstracts from court records, including deed books, order books, will books and marriage records, as well as published sources. There are also two groups of card files.
Crooks compiled his research into a unpublished work entitled, "The Children and Grand-Children of the Forebearers of the Crooks Family of Manchester, Virginia, 1635-1985." He used a particular numbering system in his research, and a key can be found in the first folder. This system was used by Crooks to organize his files. The researcher should consult the key in order to assist them in the use of the collection.
Contents List
- "The Children and Grand-Children of the Forebearers of the Crooks Family of Manchester, Virginia, 1685-1985". (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Crooks (1-2). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Crooks (4-7). (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Crooks (8-9). (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Crooks (10-11) (Moore). (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Crooks (14-15). (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Crooks (16-17). (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Crooks (26). (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Crooks (28). (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Crooks (30) (Nunnally). (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Crooks (32-33). (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Crooks (50) (Ellington). (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Crooks (52). (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
- Crooks (56). (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Crooks (62) (Fowlkes). (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Crooks (102) (Farley). (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Crooks (104) (Hatchett). (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Crooks (106) (Remey). (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Crooks (234). (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Bale/Owings. (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
- Dupuy. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ellington. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Farley. (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
- Farley, A-Z. (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- Fowlkes. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Gills. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Owings. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Family Group Sheets (A-Z). (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
- Family Group Sheets (A-C). (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Family Group Sheets (L-W). (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- Family Group Sheets (3-14). (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Family Group Sheets (16-28). (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Family Group Sheets (34-58). (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Family Group Sheets (96-470). (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Notebook - Baltimore County, Maryland Abstracts. (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
- Notebook - Baltimore County Will Book Abstracts. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Notebook - Census Abstracts. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Notebook - Deed and Will Book Abstracts. (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
- Notebook - Deed, Will, and Marriage Bonds Abstracts. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Notebook - Will Abstracts, H-Z. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Notebook - Miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
- "Dr. Robert Cobbs Mottley/John Lewis Mottley - Their Descendants and Ancestral Background" by Bessie M. Mottley, July 1964. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- "The Beaver Pond Neals of Virginia" by Carol B. Neal, March 1965. (Box 6)
- "The Hatchett Family Genealogy, 1500-1957" by Hines Hatchett. (Box Personal Papers Oversize Box 104)
- Pedigree Chart of Alfred Hatcher Wells. (Box Personal Papers Oversize Box 104)
- Card Files - 2, 4, 6, 8, 12, 14, 16. (Box 7)
- Card Files - 24, 26. (Box 8)
- Card Files - 28, 32, 48, 50, 52 (A-N). (Box 9)
- Card Files - 52 (O-Z), 56, 58, 62. (Box 10)
- Card Files - 68, 96, 102, 104, 106, 116, 124, 136. (Box 11)
- Card Files - 192, 196, 206, 232, 248, 272, 274, 544, 546, 1088. (Box 12)
- Card Files - 234, A-Z. (Box 13)
- Card Files - 1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32, 34, 6, 12, 24, 48, 96. (Box 14)
- Card Files - 104, 58, 117. (Box 15)
- Card Files - 62, 124, 248, 26, 52. (Box 16)
- Card Files - 102, 106, 234. (Box 17)
- Card Files - 192, Ancestors. (Box 18)
- Card Files - 546, 14, 28, 56, 196. (Box 19)
- Card Files - A-F and Fowlkes. (Box 20)
- Card Files - H-Z. (Box 21)
- Card Files - A-Z. (Box 22)